Finding Aid for Michigan Environmental Council records, 1925-2012
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Land Programs Director's Files
  - Other
    - Legislation
      - SB 266 (Regional Impact Coordinator), 1996 (Box 52)
      - SB 646 (Dunes), 1988-1995 (Box 52)
      - SB 1016 (Segways), 2002 (Box 52)
      - SB 1291 (Manufactured Homes), 2000 (Box 52)
    - Legislators, 1999 (Box 52)
    - Let Local Votes Count, 2000 (Box 52)
    - Michigan Economic Development Corporation, 1999 (Box 52)
    - Michigan Strategic Fund, 2004-2008 (Box 52)
    - Michigan Unitarian Universalist Social Justice Network, 2004-2005 (Box 52)
    - Millennials/New Economy, 2008 (Box 52)
    - Model Ordinance, 1997 (Box 52)
    - Natural Resources Trust Fund, 1995-1996 (Box 52)
    - Natural Rivers, 1997 (Box 52)
    - Oakland Land Conservancy: Rattalee Lake Greenway Project, 1995-1997 (Box 52)
    - Oil and Gas
      - Bills, 1996-1997 (Box 53)
      - Directional Drilling, 1997-1999 (Box 53)
      - General, 1996-1998 (Box 53)
      - Jordan River/Zaremba, 1997 (Box 53)
      - Michigan Energy Reform Coalition, 1996 (Box 53)
      - Surveillance Fees, 1996 (Box 53)
      - Used Oil Collection Network, 1990-1996 (Box 53)
    - Other Organizations' Policies, 1998-1999 (Box 53)
    - Partners
      - American Farmland Trust (AFT), 1994-1995 (Box 53)
      - Chamber of Commerce, undated (Box 53)
      - Developers, 1995 (Box 53)
      - Land Information Access Association (LIAA), 1995-1997 (Box 53)
      - Land Use Institute, 1995 (Box 53)
      - Michigan Municipal League, 1999 (Box 53)
      - Michigan Society of Planning Officials (MSPO), 1994-1998 (Box 53)
      - Michigan United Conservation Club (MUCC), 1998 (Box 53)
      - Nature Conservancy, 1995 (Box 53)
    - Peninsula Township, 1992-1994 (Box 53)
    - Planning, 1989-1994 (Box 53)
    - Real Estate Trends, 1998 (Box 53)
    - Right to Farm-Michigan Land Use Institute, 1999 (Box 53)
    - Road Bypasses, 1995-1997 (Box 53)
    - Saginaw City, 2000 (Box 53)
    - Sand Dune Review Committee, 1992-1997 (Box 53)
    - Smart Growth, 1996-2002; 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Southeast Michigan Council of Governments (SEMCOG)-Fiscal Impact, 1994-1998; 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Sprawl, 1995-1997
    - Subdivision Control Act
      - General, 1983-1997 (Box 54)
      - History, 1986-1996 (Box 54)
      - Testimony/Alert, 1995-1996 (Box 54)
    - Sustainable Development, 1994-1998 (Box 54)
    - Tools, 1991-1997 (Box 54)
    - Transit, 2002-2008 (Box 54)
    - Transportation Budgets, 2000-2002 (Box 54)
    - Transportation Economic Development Fund, 2004-2005 (Box 54)
    - Transportation-General, 1994-1996 (Box 54)
    - Trend Future, 1991-1998 (Box 54)
    - Union of Concerned Scientists, 2011-2012 (Box 54)
    - Urban Revitalization, 1993-1997 (Box 54)
    - Washtenaw County Buildout Analysis, undated (Box 54)
    - Watersheds, 1991-1997 (Box 54)
    - Wetlands, 1993-1995 (Box 54)
    - Wind, 2007-2008 (Box 54)
    - Wise Use Groups, 1994-1999 (Box 54)
- Issues and Other Staff
  The Issues and Other Staff series includes files documenting important MEC issues as well as materials produced by additional MEC staff.
  - Policy Director's Files (James Clift)
    The Policy Director's Files sub-series contains correspondence, guest lecture materials, and information related to a 2001 dispute over the General Motors Delta Township assembly plant, all of which was produced by James Clift.
    - Correspondence, 2000-2007 (Box 36)
    - General Motors Delta Township Assembly Plant Permit Dispute
      - Correspondence, 2001-2003 (Box 36)
      - MEC Internal Correspondence and Draft Writings, 2002 (Box 36)
      - Litigation Materials, 2001-2002 (Box 36)
      - Press Releases and Clippings, 2001-2002 (Box 36)
      - Proposed Final Action and Appeal Board Decision, 2002 (Box 36)
    - Guest Lecture Materials (Michigan State University, UPLA 400: Introduction to Environmental Planning), 2002 (Box 36)
  - Transportation Policy Specialist's Files (Sally Billups)
    The Transportation Policy Specialist's Files detail Sally Billups's work on the promotion of high speed rail in Michigan as well as information related to transportation legislation.
    - Ad Hoc Passenger Rail Committee Agendas, Correspondence, Reports, etc., 1997-1998 (Box 36)
    - Congressional High Speed Rail Service Field Forum, 1998 (Box 36)
    - Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act (ISTEA): Related Correspondence and Materials, 1997-1998 (Box 36)
    - MEC High Speed Rail Project, 1996-1998 (Box 36)
    - Midwest High Speed Rail Network, 1995-1997 (Box 36)
  - Environmental Communications and Community Organizing (ECCO) Initiative Coordinator's Files
    The Environmental Communications and Community Organizing (ECCO) Initiative Coordinator's Files were assembled by Wendi Tilden and document strategic planning, the meetings of various ECCO committees, and regional team activities. The ECCO Initiative, which was supported by a grant from the Beldon Fund, focused on increasing support fro pro-environmental advocacy within the greater Grand Rapids and Detroit Metropolitan areas. This sub-series also includes correspondence, newsletters and reports covering the operation and activities of ECCO, as well as digital files of photographs taken in East Lansing, Battle Creek, and Traverse City, Mich. from series of statewide public forums in summer and fall 2010.
    - Advisory Committee Meeting Minutes, 2003 (Box 36)
    - Collaborative Steering Committee Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box 36)
    - Coordinated Campaign Decision Meeting Materials, 2002 (Box 36)
    - Coordinated Campaign Feedback, 2002 (Box 36)
    - Correspondence, 2001-2003 (Box 36)
    - Newsletters, 2002-2003 (Box 36)
    - Progress Reports, 2003-2004 (Box 37)
    - Project Management Committee Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Correspondence, 2002-2004 (Box 37)
    - Project Management Committee Consultant (Dick Mark), 2004 (Box 37)
    - Regional ECCO Teams
      - Detroit, 2004-2006 (Box 37)
      - Grand Rapids, 2004 (Box 37)
      - Lake St. Clair Shoreline (The Strand), 2004-2005 (Box 37)
      - Oak, 2003-2005 (Box 37)
        (includes JPEGs and Power Point presentations on 2 CDs)
      - Southeast Michigan, 2001-2003 (Box 37)
      - Wayne County (Downriver), 2004 (Box 37)
      - West Michigan, 2001-2003 (Box 37)
    - Requests for Proposals (RFPs) and Contracts, 2003-2004 (Box 37)
    - Strategic Planning, 2001-2004 (Box 37)
    - Water Campaign Materials, 2005 (Box 37)
    - Towns Citizens Action Team, 2006 (Box 54)
    - Aerotropolis, 2008 (Box 54)
    - Agriculture, 2006-2007 (Box 54)
    - Algae Blooms/Phosphorous, 2006 undated (Box 54)
    - Ann Arbor-Downtown Detroit Transit Study, 2000-2006 (Box 54)
    - Annual Environmental Awards Celebration, 1999-2004 (Box 54)
    - Beldon Fund
      - General, 2000-2004 (Box 54)
      - Key States Gathering, 2005 (Box 55)
      - Other Key States, 2001-2003 (Box 55)
      - Proposals
        - Years 1-3, 2001 (Box 55)
        - Years 4-6, 2004 (Box 55)
      - Reports
        - Year 1, 2001-2002 (Box 55)
        - Year 2, 2002-2003 (Box 55)
        - Year 3, 2003-2004 (Box 55)
        - Year 4, 2004-2005 (Box 55)
        - Year 5, 2005-2006 (Box 55)
        - Year 6, 2007 (Box 55)
    - Boardman River Valley, 1998-1999 (Box 55)
    - Bottle Bill Campaign, 2005 (Box 55)
    - Budget
      - Years 1-3, 2001-2004 (Box 55)
      - Years 4-6, 2004-2007 (Box 55)
    - Campaign Plans, 2001-2002 (Box 55)
    - Citizens for Farmland and Open Space Preservation Ballot Measure Campaign Packet, 2004 (Box 55)
    - Collaborative Steering Committee (CSC) Years 4-6, 2004 (Box 55)
    - Community Organizing Training, 2000-2004 (Box 55)
    - Context Sensitive Design (CSD)
      - General, 2001-2003 (Box 55)
      - Judd Road Bridge, 2004 (Box 55)
    - Context Sensitive Solutions (CSS)
      - General, 2004-2005 (Box 55)
      - Woodward Study, 2002-2005 (Box 55)
    - Detroit Metro Airport, 2003-2008 (Box 55)
    - Detroit River International Crossing, 2009 (Box 55)
    - Detroit Strategy, 2005 (Box 55)
    - Detroit Transit Scoping Summary Report, 2007; 2 volumes (Box 55)
    - DNR Funding, 2003-2005 (Box 55)
    - ECCO Background, 2001-2006 (Box 55)
    - ECCO Group Information, 2001-2002 (Box 55)
    - Environmental assessment of air quality and climate change regulations (CMS Energy), 2006 (Box 55)
    - Field and Outreach, 2004 (Box 55)
    - Field Plan and Matrix and Funding, 2004 (Box 55)
    - Field Plans-Creation, 2004-2005 (Box 55)
    - Field Reports Year 4, 2004-2005 (Box 55)
    - Field/Campaign Coordinator, 2003-2004 (Box 56)
    - Fundraising, Years 1-3, 2001-2005 (Box 56)
    - Growing Louder (Newsletter), 2002-2004 (Box 56)
    - HB 6151 (Streets and Roads), 2009-2010 (Box 56)
    - Letters of Agreement, 2001-2003 (Box 56)
    - Letters of Agreement, 2004-2005; 2 folders (Box 56)
    - Letters of Agreement, 2006 (Box 56)
    - Letters of Agreement, 2007 (Box 56)
    - Lindane Shampoo, 2008 (Box 56)
    - List Use, 2001 (Box 56)
    - Media Clippings, 2003-2004 (Box 56)
    - Media Coordinator, 2001-2002 (Box 56)
    - Media Training, 2001-2004; 2 folders (Box 56)
    - Michigan Legislative Vulnerability Analysis, 2006 (Box 56)
    - Michigan Organic Food and Farm Alliance/Michigan Organic Conference, 2010-2011 (Box 56)
    - Muhammad Ali Event, 2002 (Box 56)
    - National Train Day, 2010-2011 (Box 56)
    - Organizer Meetings Years 1-3, 2001-2003 (Box 56)
    - Project Coordinator, 2002-2005 (Box 56)
    - Project Management Committee (PMC)
      - Years 1-3, 2001-2003 (Box 56)
      - Years 4-5, 2004-2005 (Box 57)
    - Railways
      - High-Speed Rail, 1991-1998 (Box 57)
      - Lansing-to-Detroit Passenger Rail, 1999-2002 (Box 57)
      - Michigan by Rail, 2010-2011 (Box 57)
        - Rail Forum, Traverse City, MI, photographs, 2010; zip file
        - Rail Forum, Battle Creek, MI, photographs, 2010; zip file
        - Rail Forum, East Lansing, MI, photographs, 2010; zip file
    - Roads
      - I-94, 2000-2004 (Box 57)
      - I-375, 1999-2000 (Box 57)
      - US-23, 2000 (Box 57)
      - US-31, 1999-2002 (Box 57)
      - US-131, 2000-2004 (Box 57)
    - Small Grants
      - Years 1-3, 2002-2003 (Box 57)
      - Years 4, 2004-2005 (Box 57)
      - Years 5, 2005 (Box 57)
      - Years 6, 2006 (Box 57)
    - Training: Grassroots 101, Framing the Debate, Media 101, 2001 (Box 57)
    - Transit Roadshow, 2009 (Box 57)
    - Transportation Funding Task Force, 2008 (Box 57)
    - Transportation (General), 1998-2009 (Box 58)
    - Traverse City Fundraiser with Governor Milliken, 2001 (Box 58)
  - Land Use Heroes Project
    The Land Use Heroes Project sub-series documents a 2001 MEC project that sought to recognize environmental leadership in each of the districts of the state legislature.
    - Correspondence and Planning Materials, 2001-2002 (Box 37)
    - Organizational Surveys, 2001-2002 (Box 37)
    - Photographs, 2001-2002; 1 optical disks CD-ROMs (Box 37)
      includes a JPEG image on CD and images in a Microsoft Publisher document on CD
  - Litigation
    The Litigation sub-series includes correspondence, background information, and court documents related to seven different legal cases in which MEC was involved.
    - Friends of Crystal River v Kuras Properties, et al.: Correspondence, Legal Documents, etc., 1996-1999; 2 folders (Box 37)
    - Grayling Generation Station Tire-Derived Fuel (TDF) Tests and Related Materials, 2001 (Box 37)
    - Hillman Power Company Tire-Derived Fuel Permit Petitions and Related Materials, 2002 (Box 37)
    - K & K Construction v Michigan Department of Natural Resources (Box 38)
      - Clippings, 1997-1998 (Box 38)
      - MEC Correspondence, Press Releases, and Related Materials, 1996-1998 (Box 38)
      - Various Legal Documents, 1997; 2 folders (Box 38)
    - Nemeth v Abonmarche Development: Correspondence, Legal Documents, etc.,1997-1998, 2 folders (Box 38)
    - Platte Lake Improvement Association v Michigan Department of Natural Resources: Correspondence, Legal Documents, etc., 1996-1997 (Box 38)
    - Power Supply Cost Recovery Litigation (Various Cases): Correspondence, Legal Documents, etc., 1999-2002 (Box 38)
  - Polluter Pay Legislation
    The Polluter Pay Legislation sub-series details MEC's participation in various pieces of legislation that dealt with corporate liability for cleaning up polluted areas. The files include correspondence, draft legislation, and related materials.
    - Act 307 (Comprehensive Cleanup Program)
      - MEC Statement, 1989 (Box 39)
      - Department Responses to Public Comments, 1989 (Box 39)
      - Public Comments, 1989-1990; 3 folders (Box 39)
    - HB 4596 (Polluter Pay Rollback): MEC Statement, 1995 (Box 39)
    - HB 5878 (Amendment to Environmental Response Act): Correspondence, Press Releases, etc., 1990 (Box 39)
    - SB 375 (Polluter Pay for Cleanup Bill)
      - Clippings and Press Releases, 1990 (Box 39)
      - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 39)
      - MEC Grassroots Campaign, 1990 (Box 39)
      - MEC Lobby Day: Publicity, References, Agendas, etc., 1990 (Box 39)
      - Public Testimony, 1989-1990 (Box 39)
- Grants
  The Grants series includes applications, correspondence, budgets, and reports related to grants awarded to MEC by a variety of foundations and agencies. Significant files include those detailing MEC's involvement with: the American Foundation, the Beldon Fund (related to ECCO and MEC strategic planning and endowment development), the Frey Foundation (for environmental education and MEC's Land Stewardship Initiative), the Joyce Foundation (various pollution prevention and Great Lakes management initiatives), the Kellogg Foundation (community planning and urban development projects), and the Mott Foundation (MEC's Land Stewardship Initiative and Smart Growth projects).
  - Americana Foundation, 1994-2002 (Box 39)
  - American Public Transportation Association, 2002 (Box 39)
  - Arcus Foundation, 2002-2003 (Box 39)
  - Austin Memorial Foundation, 2001 (Box 39)
  - Beldon Fund
    - Environment and Health, 2003 (Box 39)
    - Environmental Communications and Community Organizing (ECCO) Initiative
      - Report, 2002 (Box 39)
      - Strategic Planning: Meetings, Correspondence, Reports, etc., 2000-2002; 2 folders (Box 39)
    - "Making the Environment Matter", 1999-2000 (Box 40)
    - MEC Endowment/Major Donor Development Program, 1998-2004 (Box 40)
    - MEC Membership Initiatives, 1991-1998 (Box 40)
    - Michigan Strategic Planning Project, 1999-2001; 2 folders (Box 40)
    - General Funding Information, 2004 (Box 40)
  - Clear the Air, 2003 (Box 40)
  - Community Foundation for Southeastern Michigan, 2000 (Box 40)
  - Conservation Fund, 2003-2004 (Box 40)
  - Dart Foundation, 1998-2005; 3 folders (Box 40)
  - Energy Foundation, 2001-2004; 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Freemont Area Foundation, 2005 (Box 40)
  - Frey Foundation
    - Environmental Education, 2000-2001 (Box 40)
    - Land Stewardship Initiative, 1994-2005; 3 folders (Box 40)
  - Grand Rapids Community Foundation, 2001-2002 (Box 41)
  - Great Lakes Protection Fund, 1998 (Box 41)
  - Harder Foundation, 1993-1994 (Box 41)
  - Hewlitt Foundation, 2002 (Box 41)
  - Hope for the Dunes Grass Roots Trust Fund, 1995 (Box 41)
  - Izaak Walton League, 1999-2005; 4 folders (Box 41)
  - Joyce Foundation
    - Algae Project, 2005 (Box 41)
    - Autos and the Environment Initiative, 2001-2003 (Box 41)
    - "Governing the Great Lakes" Project, 2002-2003 (Box 41)
    - "Great Lakes Leaks", 2003-2004 (Box 41)
    - "Greening the Great Lakes" Project, 2002 (Box 41)
    - High Speed Rail, 1998 (Box 41)
    - Lake Erie Ecosystem Organizing Project, 2004 (Box 41)
    - Midwest Power Plant Campaign, 2000-2003; 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Pollution Prevention and Energy Efficiency, 1994-1997 (Box 41)
    - "Protecting the Great Lakes" Project, 2003 (Box 41)
    - "Reshaping Michigan's Key Policy Decisions on Pollution Prevention, Energy Efficiency, and High Speed Rail", 1997-1999 (Box 41)
    - Miscellaneous Grants
      - 1982-1985 (Box 41)
      - 1988-2005, 2 folders (Box 42)
  - Kellogg Foundation
    - Capacity Building for Endowment, 2004-2006 (Box 42)
    - "Exploring Questions of Density" (Large Lot Zoning) Project, 2002-2003 (Box 42)
    - "Governing the Great Lakes" Project, 2002-2004 (Box 42)
    - People and Land (PAL) Program
      - Context Sensitive Design (Community Planning), 2003-2004 (Box 42)
      - Smart Investments in Michigan, 2001 (Box 42)
    - Miscellaneous Reports, 1993-1997 (Box 42)
  - Kennedy Foundation, 1986-1990 (Box 42)
  - Kresge Foundation, 2005 (Box 42)
  - Lloyd and Mabel Johnson Foundation, 2005 (Box 42)
  - Madar Association, 1997-1998 (Box 42)
  - McGregor Fund, 1999 (Box 42)
  - Michigan Department of Environmental Quality Coastal Management Program, 2005 (Box 42)
  - Michigan Department of Natural Resources Coastal Management Program, 1994-1995 (Box 42)
  - Mott Foundation
    - Land Stewardship Initiative (LSI), 1994-2005; 2 folders (Box 42)
    - Land Use Mini-Grant Initiative, 1994-1997 (Box 43)
    - MEC General Planning, 1993-1994 (Box 43)
    - "Race and Culture in the Environmental Movement" (submitted by ACCESS), 2002 (Box 43)
    - Smart Growth, 1998-2000 (Box 43)
    - Miscellaneous Grants, 1986-1995 (Box 43)
  - Needmor Fund, 1990 (Box 43)
  - Pew Charitable Trusts, 1997-1998 (Box 43)
  - Pulte Homes Charitable Giving Office, 2004-2005 (Box 43)
  - Rockefeller Family Fund, 1997-2005 (Box 43)
  - State Environmental Leadership Program (SELP), 2001 (Box 43)
  - Skillman Foundation, 2002-2003 (Box 43)
  - Surdna Foundation, 1997-2004 (Box 43)
  - Tides Foundation, 2004 (Box 43)
  - Towsley Foundation, 1997-2002 (Box 43)
  - Turner Foundation, 1997-2002 (Box 43)
  - U.S. Environmental Protection Agency's Development, Community and Environment Division, 2001-2002 (Box 43)
  - W. Alton Jones Foundation (Automotive Initiative, Endocrine Disrupter Education, and Pollution Prevention), 1989-2000 (Box 43)
  - Wege Foundation, 1999-2003 (Box 43)
  - Multiple Foundations: Smart Growth Proposals, 2001-2002 (Box 43)
- Member Organizations
  The Member Organizations series contains information about current and past MEC member organizations. Files include membership applications, correspondence, publications, and additional content related to individual groups. The series also contains member questionnaires and membership rosters from 1988 to 2001 that chart the growth and development of MEC.
  - Arab Community Center for Economic and Social Services (ACCESS), 1997 (Box 43)
  - Alcona County Environmental Coalition, 1996 (Box 43)
  - American Indian Health, 1998 (Box 43)
  - Anglers of the AuSable, 1997 (Box 43)
  - AuSable Conservation Trust, 1990-1992 (Box 43)
  - Cadillac Area Citizens for Clean Air, undated (Box 43)
  - Citizens for Alternatives to Chemical Contamination, 1993-1996 (Box 43)
  - Citizens Against Pollution, 1995 (Box 43)
  - Citizens' Resistance at Fermi 2 (CRAFT), 1996 (Box 43)
  - Clean Water Action, 1993-1998 (Box 43)
  - Clinton River Watershed Council, undated, 1997 (Box 43)
  - Concerned Citizen Council for Rural Awareness (CRAW), 1995 (Box 43)
  - Concerned Citizens of Acme Township, 2001 (Box 43)
  - Detroit Audubon Society, 1995 (Box 43)
  - Detroiters Working for Environmental Justice (DWEJ), 1998 (Box 43)
  - Don't Waste Michigan, 1997 (Box 43)
  - Downriver Citizens for a Safe Environment, 1997 (Box 43)
  - East Michigan Environmental Action Council (EMEAC), 1993-1996 (Box 43)
  - Ecology Center of Ann Arbor, 1995 (Box 43)
  - Environmental Information Center, undated (Box 43)
  - Environmental Issues Commission, 1997 (Box 43)
  - Friends of the Detroit River, 1996 (Box 44)
  - Friends of the Jordan River, 1996 (Box 44)
  - Friends of the Rouge River, 1992-1993 (Box 44)
  - Grand Rapids Audubon Club, 1996 (Box 44)
  - Great Lakes Bioregional Land Conservancy, 1998 (Box 44)
  - Huron River Watershed Council, 1997 (Box 44)
  - Kalamazoo Environmental Council, 1996-1997 (Box 44)
  - Lake Michigan Federation, 1995-1998 (Box 44)
  - League of Conservation Voters (LCV) Education Fund, undated (Box 44)
  - League of Women Voters, Michigan (LWV-MI), 1989-1994 (Box 44)
  - LINK, 1995 (Box 44)
  - Local Motion, 2001 (Box 44)
  - Lone Tree Council, 1995 (Box 44)
  - Metropolitan Organizing Strategy Enabling Strength (MOSES), 1999 (Box 44)
  - Michigan Audubon Society, 1994-1997 (Box 44)
  - Michigan Chapter of the North American Lake Management Society, 1996 (Box 44)
  - Michigan Citizens Against Toxic Substances, 1996 (Box 44)
  - Michigan Citizens for Water Conservation, 2001 (Box 44)
  - Michigan Environmental Health Association, 1996 (Box 44)
  - Michigan Ecumenical Consultation on Christianity and Ecology (MECCE), 1996-1998 (Box 44)
  - Michigan Lake and Stream Associations, 1992 (Box 44)
  - Michigan Land Trustees, Inc., 1998 (Box 44)
  - Michigan Land Use Institute (MLUI), 1995-1998 (Box 44)
  - Michigan League of Conservation Voters (LCV), undated (Box 44)
  - Michigan Natural Areas Council, 1992-1993 (Box 44)
  - Michigan Organic Food and Farm Alliance, 1995 (Box 44)
  - Michigan Recycling Coalition, 1995 (Box 44)
  - Mid-Michigan Environmental Action Council (Mid-MEAC), 1995 (Box 44)
  - Mullett Lake Area Preservation Society, 1998 (Box 44)
  - Natural Resource Stewards, 1998 (Box 44)
  - Northern Michigan Environmental Action Council (NMEAC), 1993-1995 (Box 44)
  - Oakland Land Conservancy, 1996-1997 (Box 44)
  - Oakwood Environmental Concern Association, 1990-1995 (Box 44)
  - Pottawatomie Land Trust, 1995 (Box 44)
  - Public Interest Research Group in Michigan (PIRGIM), 1991-1997 (Box 44)
  - Rails to Trails Conservancy, 1990-1991 (Box 44)
  - Republicans for Environmental Protection (REP America), 1999 (Box 44)
  - Romulus Environmentalists Care About People (RECAP), 2001 (Box 44)
  - Sierra Club Mackinac Chapter, 1993-1995 (Box 44)
  - Southeast Michigan Coalition on the Environment and Jewish Life (SEMCOEJL), undated (Box 44)
  - Southeast Michigan Land Conservancy, 1995-1998 (Box 44)
  - Southwest Detroit Environmental Vision Project (SDEVP), 1996-1999 (Box 44)
  - Student Environmental Action Coalition (SEAC), 1996-1997 (Box 44)
  - Student Environmental Alliance (SEA), 1995 (Box 44)
  - Sustainable University of Michigan, 2001 (Box 44)
  - Three Lakes Association, 1997-1998 (Box 44)
  - Tip of the Mitt Watershed Council, 1991-1996 (Box 44)
  - Transportation Riders United, undated (Box 44)
  - Upper Peninsula Environmental Council (UPEC), 1992 (Box 44)
  - West Michigan Environmental Action Council (WMEAC), 1990-1996 (Box 44)
  - Member Dues and Benefits, 2006-2008 (Box 44)
  - Member Rosters, 1988-2001 (Box 44)
  - Member Surveys, undated, 2003-2004 (Box 44)
- Publications
  The Publications series includes various publications produced for MEC members as well as the wider environmental and legislative communities. Biweekly reports to member organizations provide a thorough representation of MEC activities while the Lansing Update and MEC Capital Update document activities in the state legislative and executive branches. The series also contains a variety of other publications (such as several editions of the Michigan Environmental Briefing Book) and press releases, but does not include the Michigan Environmental Report (MEC's member newsletter), which is catalogued elsewhere in the Bentley Library.
  - Biweekly Reports to MEC Member Organizations
    - 1991 (Box 44)
    - 1992 (Box 44)
    - 1994 (Box 44)
    - 1995 (Box 44)
    - 1996 (Box 45)
    - 1997 (Box 45)
    - 1998 (Box 45)
    - 1999 (Box 45)
  - Greenline, 1995-1996 (Box 45)
  - Lansing Update
    - 1983 (Box 45)
    - 1984 (Box 45)
    - 1985 (Box 45)
    - 1986 (Box 45)
    - 1988 (Box 45)